CAMERON BEAM

A mental health industry leader with a strong focus on program development and creative problem-solving to improve the patient experience. Over 8 years of practice managing teams, building collaborative stakeholder relationships, and implementing value-driven initiatives to improve access, quality, and cost of care.

Experience

2018-01 **–** 2020-01

Qualified Professional

A Small Miracle LLC., Raleigh, NC

- Review all verification and documentation of services per the NC DHHS Records Management and Documentation Manual
- Conduct and document clinical and employee supervisory visits, and ensure accuracy and completion of client records
- Lead annual performance evaluations, direct care staff development plans, disciplinary meetings/documentation with direct care staff
- Develop individualized short term goals, task analysis and interventions for clients and ensuring information is entered into the Electronic Health Records system
- Review weekly billing to assess utilization of services
- Assist the recipient and families with procuring appropriate resources and services in the community
- Represent A Small Miracle at community events and public policy initiatives
- Trained staff in behavioral de-escalation and intervention measures

2012-12 -Current

Support Professional Team Lead

Autism Society of North Carolina, Raleigh, NC

- Review the client's progress on an ongoing basis to align goals and strategies with the client's level of ability
- Manage client's family and/or group home staff in order to keep open communication regarding the client's progress
- Coordinate with the client's case manager and other professionals involved in providing services to

Personal Info

Address

Raleigh, NC

Phone

919-696-7902

E-mail

ctbeam2@ncsu.edu

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/cameronbeam/

Education

2016-01

Bachelor of Arts: Psychology

North Carolina State University - Raleigh, NC Focus on neurological, biological, and human factor psychology

2013-01

Associate of Arts

Wake Technical Community College -Raleigh, NC

Skills

TECHNICAL: EHR Systems,
Microsoft Office Products,
MacOS Software, OnTarget
Medicaid Software,
Advanced Intervention
Training

FUNCTIONAL: Customer Service, Program Development, Public the participant

- Co-Created the Quality Improvement Committee, which reviewed summaries of complaints, incidences, and feedback from surveys, focus groups, interviews, and Personal Outcome Measures
- Reviewed survey tools and implemented process improvement initiatives for data collection
- Established participant/family-oriented improvement projects.

2010-12 - Support Professional 2012-12

Autism Society Of North Carolina, Raleigh, NC

- Ensured services are provided with a commitment to CQL's basic assurances of health and safety and work to meet the personal outcomes of individuals we support
- Utilized required systems, policies and procedures to ensure fiscal and operational responsibility
- Provide appropriate training in independence, rights, self-care, communication, social skills, recreational and leisure skills, and/or vocational and pre-vocational skills.
- Documented each unit of service in the prescribed fashion on the progress note and the time sheet, which was consistently submitted to the supervisor in a timely manner

Policy, Patient Safety, Strategic Planning, Patient Engagement, Staff Development